## Jacob C. Lutz

#### jacob@colemanlutz.com

#### **Software Development**

Entry-level software developer who takes pride in craftsmanship of quality software. Possesses working knowledge of Object Orientation Programming and source control. Has worked in C++, C#, Ada, Java, Ruby, Python, HTML, and CSS, and is familiar with Debian-based distributions of Linux OS.

#### **Education**

Indiana Institute of Technology	Fort Wayne, IN
Bachelor of Science, Software Engineering	Expected May 2015
Minor in <i>Networking</i>	GPA 3.8/4.0

## **Professional Experience**

## **Nexus Technology Partners**

**August 2013 - August 2014** 

A professional information technology consulting company located in downtown Fort Wayne, IN, whose main purpose is to provide businesses with IT advice and support.

#### Software Development Intern

- Worked on creating a public key encryption infrastructure to be used for employee authentication
- Created and maintained Subversion source control server
- Provided training on using source control
- Recovered and secured client websites
- Provided Windows 8 support

# **Professional Teaching Experience Indiana Institute of Technology**

<u>Lab Assistant</u>
August 2014 – Present

- Oversee Automation Lab
- Teach students to use high-level scripting languages to control machinery

#### **Teaching Assistant**

August 2013 – December 2013

- Helped create curriculum for freshman Computer Science majors
- Presented weekly on introductory computer science topics

#### **Certifications/Student Organizations**

•	Member of Indiana Tech Resident Assistant Staff	August 2013 – May 2015
•	Treasurer of Indiana Tech Student Ambassadors	August 2014 – May 2015
•	Member of Indiana Tech Collegiate Cyber Defense Team	August 2012 – October 2013
•	Vice President of Indiana Tech Collegiate Cyber Defense Club	August 2013 – May 2014
•	Member of Indiana Tech ACM Chapter	August 2012 – August 2013
•	CompTIA Net+ Certification	December 2011
•	CompTIA A+ Certification	May 2011